# **NIRAJ CHAVAN**

**UI / Web Developer** 

**Email** - nirajd327@gmail.com **Phone** - +91 96071 95436

Portfolio - https://niraj-chavan.herokuapp.com/
Linkedin - https://in.linkedin.com/in/niraj-chavan-8267bb98

7<sup>th</sup> Heaven, B-404, B Wing, Sr. No. - 6, Hissa No. - 3, D. N. Parande Park, Dhanori, Pune - 411015

# **Career Summary**

UI Developer with 7 years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex e-commerce sites. An energetic and imaginative young Web Developer who is able to work alongside other talented IT professionals in creating websites to the very highest standards.

Skilled in developing and achieving technical objectives and goals to support the organization vision while managing & developing projects of web application.

# **Experience – (7 Years)**

# **UI DEVELOPER, SCHLUMBERGER**

23 Sept 2019 – Present, Location – Pune

Help to integrate Wijmo in angular component with engineering team. Build reusable libraries and code for future use. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability. Reviewing requirements and design to build new UI features.

#### SENIOR UI ENGINEER, XPANXION INTERNATIONAL PVT. LTD.

31 Jan 2017 – 20 Sept 2019, Location – Pune

Implementation of angular custom reusable components, JWT token implementation, performance optimization and API integration.

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER, CONNECT | 91 WEB SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD.

(Currently known as Polyscripts Infotech Pvt. Ltd.) 14 Dec 2015 – 30 Jan 2017, Location – Pune

UI enhancement designs for better user experience, convert PSD into HTML and make the websites compatible with all browsers.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, WHITECODE IT SOLUTION

03 July 2014 – 11 Dec 2015, Location – Pune

Responsible for participating in the full life cycle of new website development and maintaining best practice procedures in all areas of work.

# **Technical Strength**

HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap 4/5, JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, Angular, ReactJS, Express JS, Node JS, GraphQL, JSON, WordPress, Python, Flask, SVN, GIT, MySQL, MongoDB, Jira, Rally, Microsoft Azure, Webpack, Karma, Jasmine, Jest

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth: 07-August-1992 Marital Status: Unmarried Nationality: Indian

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Marathi

# **Education**

### **BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (COMPUTER ENGG.)**

Dr. D. Y. Patil Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pune University

July 2011 – June 2014 Grade (%): 63.89

### **DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING**

Y. B. Patil Polytechnic, Pune (Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education)

July 2008 – May 2011 Grade (%): 83.03

#### SECONDRY SCHOOL EDUCATION

Sharada Vidyamandir, Maharashtra Board
June 2007 – July 2008 Grade (%): 86.46

# **Projects**

## **PROJECT NAME - FIELD LOGISTIC MODULE**

### Role and Responsibility -

Participate in all aspects of product development, from requirement analysis to product release. To analyze and debug the application to find a solution for incidents. Design and develop user interface using angular best practices. To integrate Wijmo Flexgrid components into FLM application. Optimize performance of the application. Responsible for ownership of the application code base which includes maintaining the integrity of the code, defining/enforcing standards and best practices, performing and participating in code reviews.

**Team Size –** 10 **Skills –** Angular 7, HTML, SCSS, Wijmo Flexgrid, MongoDB, MS Azure, **Role –** UI Developer JavaScript, ECMAScript, Typescript, Flux Architecture, Git

#### **PROJECT NAME - eCOM SHOP**

### Role and Responsibility -

Participate in activities including UI design, development and support complex web application. Meeting with the client team to discuss user interface ideas. Reviewing application requirements and interface designs. Writing application code by following React workflows. Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

**Team Size** – 3 **Skills** – React JS, Express JS, MongoDB, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap,

**Role –** UI Developer Node JS, Heroku

#### **PROJECT NAME - K7 SECURITY**

### Role and Responsibility -

To build dashboard for end customers to manage multiple devices from online website account. Develop software solutions using industry best practices and in the area of security and performance in a web and architecture environment. Collaborates with team and business owners in the design and analysis phases as part of self-organizing feature teams. Maintain source-code repository, participate in Code Reviews, and conduct design reviews. Participate in deployment of code into production.

**Team Size** – 8 **Skills** – Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap, JHipster, JavaScript,

**Role** – UI Developer Typescript, Git, Rally

#### **PROJECT NAME - SCOPERETAIL**

# Role and Responsibility -

Design and developed UI Interface with optimized solution for E-commerce retail product. To create custom angular 5 components for Internal framework. To create UI mock-ups, wire frames and responsive design using HTML 5, Bootstrap 4 and JavaScript. Best solutions for performance optimization techniques and unit testing strategy. Build deployment strategy and micro web-based service architecture. Integrated web rest API with front end application. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability.

**Team Size –** 22 **Skills** – Angular 7, HTML 5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, Typescript, Git,

**Role –** UI Developer Jira, Jasmine, Karma

#### **PROJECT NAME - CERTASLIM**

#### Role and Responsibility -

Design and develop high performance web applications using Front-end technologies. Use mark-up languages like HTML to create user-friendly web pages. Develop new user-facing features. Build reusable code and libraries for future use. Create quality mockups and prototypes. Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability. Work closely with juniors and provide strong code reviews and feedback. Continually evaluate emerging frameworks and technologies to identify opportunities, trends and best practices that strengthen the development team.

**Team Size** – 6 **Skills** – Angular, HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 3, jQuery, JavaScript, Git, Zoho

Role – UI Developer